人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  紫玉  面条打包子  油炸电风扇
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   擦擦   Jessie
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监：阿好
你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第十八集
这是我这辈子最幸运的一天
This is the best day of my life.
凯蒂  我只想说
Listen, Candi, I just want to say...
我觉得你很特别
I think you're really special.
干什么
Hey! What--
你们都不敲门的吗
Don't you knock?
你偷了我们的钱  我们得要回来
You stole our money. We want it back.
你们是尼日利亚诈骗犯
Are you the Nigerian scammers?
真不敢相信你们真是尼日亚利人
I can't believe you're actually Nigerian.
五百块  快点
500 bucks. Now.
凯蒂
Candi...
你陷害我  我还以为我们之间是真情
You set me up? I thought we had something.
拜托  各位
Hey, come on, g-guys.
严格说来诈骗诈骗犯不能算犯罪
It's not technically a crime to scam a scammer!
不过切掉一个人的肠子
But it is a crime to cut out a man's intestines
套他脑门上算犯罪
and make him wear them as a hat.
等等  你打算杀了我
Wait, you plan to kill me?
也许吧
Probably.
好吧  这可犯了大错了
Okay, that's a big mistake.
是的  你们最好快逃吧
Yeah, you better get out of here.
快点儿  趁着还能逃
Right now, while you still can.
我们不能再这么玩儿下去了
We have to stop meeting like this.
见到你总是很高兴的
I'm always so happy to see you.
再有下次  里昂  我肯定在度假
Next time this happens, Leon, I'm gonna be on vacation.
我猜陶先生毫发未损
I gather that Mr. Tao is intact.
-是的  -芬奇儿
- He is. - Finchy!
而且看起来视死如归  应对自如
And seemingly unfazed by his most recent brush with death.
你开啥玩笑  人家很烦恼的
Are you kidding? I'm distraught.
那女人让我芳心寸断
That woman ripped out my beating heart.
咱去喝一杯吧
Let's go get me a drink.
我得借酒浇愁啊
I need to work through this.
里瑟先生  麻烦尽快跟里昂分道扬镳
Mr. Reese, please part ways with Leon as quickly as possible.
我们又接到一个新号码
We've received another number.
这是我一整天听到的最好的消息了
That's the best news I've heard all day.
你得马上动身
You'll have to leave immediately.
得出趟门了
There's some travel required.
去大西洋城
You're going to Atlantic City.
好了  芬奇  我到了
All right, Finch, I'm here.
跟我说说我们的新号码吧
So tell me about our new number.
他叫卢・米切尔  退休的修表匠
His name is Lou Mitchell, a retired watch repairman.
鳏夫  无子
He's a widower with no children.
妻子玛里琳六个月前死于癌症
His wife Marilyn died of cancer six months ago.
我找到的资料都发你了
I'm sending you everything I was able to find.
可跟的不多啊  芬奇
Not much to go on, Finch.
卢就像他这个年龄段的人一样  没有手机
Like many people his age, Lou has no cell phone,
没有电邮  几乎没有网络数据资料
no email, almost no digital footprint.
我们必须得亲身去探
We'll have to use a more hands-on approach.
看到他了
Got him in my sights now.
你
You!
要吃点爆米花得费多大劲啊
What's a guy have to do to get a little popcorn around here?
卢今天不太走运啊  芬奇
Luck isn't on Lou's side, Finch.
看来他今晚输了不少钱
Looks like he's burned through some cash tonight.
直接告诉我哪儿搞爆米花
Just point me in the direction of the pop secret.
我自己来吧
I'll make it myself, huh?
他玩的是百家乐
Seems his game of choice is baccarat.
他喜欢经典
He enjoys the classics.
这种很简单  双方
It's designed to be simple. Two hands.
玩家  庄家
Player, banker.
猜哪方手里的牌加起来最接近九
You guess which hand adds up closest to nine.
我当过国际间谍  芬奇
I was an international spy, Finch.
我知道怎么玩百家乐
I know how to play baccarat.
天牌九点  庄家赢
A natural nine. Banker bet wins.
你害我关节炎都发作了
You make my arthritis flare up.
真遗憾  卢  明天好运点
Sorry, Lou. Better luck tomorrow.
看来他是常客  芬奇
Sounds like he's a regular, Finch.
也许卢在维纳斯赌场输得太多了
Maybe Lou has lost too much money at the Venus Casino.
我们得查查他的财政状况
We should look into his finances.
第二天  没发现威胁
Day two. No sign of a threat.
谁会想伤害个老人呢
Who would want to hurt an old man anyway?
不管卢以前如何  现在都就剩一张嘴了
Whoever Lou used to be, he's all bark now.
快点  快点  我等到花儿都谢了
Come on, come on. I'm growing roots here.
黑进卢的银行账户了吗
Any luck hacking Lou's bank account?
他没有网上账户
He has no online access.
我不得不黑进整间银行
I'm having to hack his entire bank.
我进去了
I'm in.
看来卢的金库要空了
And it looks like Lou's coffers are nearly empty.
他妻子死时他几乎花光了一切
He withdrew almost everything at the time of his wife's death.
之后就一直依靠社保为生
He's been living on social security ever since.
他用不属于他的钱在赌
If he's gambling money he doesn't have,
可能是陷入高利贷的麻烦了
he could be in trouble with loan sharks.
修表匠没戴表
A watch repairman without a watch
也没戴婚戒
and no wedding ring.
也许他把值钱的东西都卖了
Maybe he had to pawn off all their valuables.
看来赌瘾
Seems likely that a gambling addiction
是威胁来源
is the root of the danger.
芬奇  我以前见过卢这种手
Finch, I've seen hands like Lou's before.
手指全断过
All of his fingers were broken.
我猜  很久以前在大西洋城
My guess, a long time ago in Atlantic City,
他惹怒过黑手党
he could have rubbed the mob the wrong way.
-卢  -凯利
- Lou. - Kelly.
简直像在往我的坟墓里倒
It's like you're pouring me into my grave.
这个新品  喝起来像泥
This new stuff, it tastes like mud.
总有一天  卢  我要把你
One day, Lou, I am gonna throw you
从前门扔出去
right out the front door.
面对现实吧  凯利  我缠定你了
Face it, Kelly, you're stuck with me.
我变鬼都混在这里
My ghost is gonna haunt this booth
赖到这餐馆化成灰为止
until the diner crumbles to the ground.
怎么了  出什么事了
What? What? What's the matter?
有人向老板开价买这块地
The owner got an offer on the place.
那个赌场暴发户  马克里斯
That flashy casino guy, Makris,
-要扩建停车场什么的  -上帝啊
- wants overflow parking or something. - Oh, God.
你告诉他
Well, you tell him--
你告诉他  先过了我这关
you tell him he's got to go through me.
我告诉他哪儿停他那些该死的车
I'll show him where to park his damn cars.
我似乎有发现了  里瑟先生
I may have found something, Mr. Reese.
《纽约日报》上卢结婚启事的档案
Lou's Wedding Announcement in an archival copy of the New York Journal.
在1972年
1972.
有什么有用的
Anything useful?
看来是玛里琳的一位朋友把她交给新郎的
Seems that a friend of Marilyn's gave her away at the wedding.
这应该是新娘父亲的工作
如果卢跟黑手党有牵连
If Lou was involved with the mob,
也许她的父母不同意婚事
her parents might not have approved.
我去请卡特查一下
I'll ask Carter to look into it.
我去探探卢的负债情况
I'll try to determine the extent of Lou's debts.
也许是他以前的赌债找上门了
It may be that his gambling past is coming back to haunt him.
卢・米切尔的名字出现在七十年代的
Lou Mitchell pops up in Jersey organized crime records
泽西集团犯罪记录中  颇受了罪
in the 1970s, got his ass handed to him.
赌债和被捕让他惹上了黑手党人
Gambling debts and arrests got him in trouble with some wise guys.
那些黑手党人现在还管着那里吗
You know if those wise guys still run that part of town?
没了  都老黄历了
Nah, they're ancient history.
不过现在更糟了
But it's even worse these days.
维纳斯赌场毒品问题泛滥
A lot of drug problems around the Venus Casino.
缉毒组的说他们正在调查
Narcotics tells me they're looking into the guy
那里的老板
who runs the place.
-谢了  舍曼斯基  -没问题
- Thanks, Szymanski. - You got it.
卡特  这是你要的斯蒂尔斯警探的受惩报告
Carter, I got that disciplinary report you wanted on Detective Stills.
就有普通的滥用权力
It's just your garden variety abuse of power.
谢了  铁尼
Thanks, Terney.
没问题
You got it.
乔丝
Joss.
比彻警探
Detective Beecher.
我在想
So I was thinking,
既然我们去欧文岛的路上你没开枪打我
since you didn't shoot me on the way out to Owen Island--
那这样吧  过来
Yeah, you know what? Uh, come on.
也许这就是你默许
Then maybe that's your way of saying
我带你去"爱之屋"
I should take you to Il Cuore.
阳台桌如何
Table on the terrace?
-让我想想好吗  -想快一点
- Can I think about it? - But think quick.
我定了周五的位子
I made us a reservation Friday night.
与此同时
In the meantime,
也许你能帮我查间赌场
maybe you can help me look into this casino.
里瑟先生  我看你回到赌场了
Mr. Reese, I see you've returned to the casino.
-卢上赌桌了吗  -马上要上了
- Is Lou at the tables? - He will be soon.
干什么呢  他都没钱了
To do what? He has no money.
一千五
$1,500.
跟他刚用支票换好的那堆筹码说去
Tell that to the wad of bills he just forked over to the cashier.
看来卢的债台更高了
Looks like Lou's going further into debt.
赌场会用会员卡来锁定老顾客
The casino attracts regular gamblers through a loyalty card system.
如果我们获取到卢的
If we could access Lou's,
应该就能查清他的赌博史
it would have information on his entire gambling history.
有办法黑入那个系统吗
Any way you can hack into the system?
从昨天就开始试了
I've been trying since yesterday.
赌场在安保方面颇费心思
Casinos invest heavily in their security,
防火墙有点棘手
and their firewalls are of the tricky sort.
不过阿喀琉斯之踵永远存在  那就是他们的贪婪
But every Achilles has a heel, and theirs is greed.
他们的视频二十一点游戏是联网的
Their video blackjack game is connected to the internet
好让在线用户也能输钱进去
so that online users can lose money too.
我现在正在跟你对玩
I'm playing against you right now.
你玩儿得不好噢
You're not doing very well.
赢不是目的
Winning is not the goal.
这游戏一心希望我去玩
The game is so eager to let me play
我的恶意程序可以趁机溜进去了
that it's allowed my malware to slip through.
提醒我千万别跟你过不去  芬奇
Remind me never to cross you, Finch.
别跟我赌  破坏运气
Don't bet against me. Bad luck.
我想你能守住的
I think you could hold your own.
查查这个人的身份  芬奇
I'm sending you someone to ID, Finch.
这人一幅当家作主的样子
Guy acts like he owns the place.
他就是  达里恩・马克里斯
Indeed he does. Darien Makris.
在当地小有名气  他是赌场的老板
Bit of a local celebrity. He owns the casino.
卡特警探提醒我注意他
Detective Carter put him on my radar.
警方正在调查他贩卖可卡因的事
The police have been looking into him for cocaine distribution,
但他从未被起诉
but he's never been charged.
天啊  真遗憾
Jeez, I'm sorry.
看来我真的破坏了你的运气
Looks like I did ruin your luck.
有没有试过我们的老虎机
Listen, have you tried our slots?
来吧  我给你免费转一下
Come on, I'll give you a free spin.
埃里克会带你过去
Eric here will point you in the right direction.
好了  我获取保安权限了
Okay, I've given myself security access,
只要卢把卡一插
so as soon as Lou swipes his card,
我就能远程查看他的历史了
I should be able to view his history remotely.
里瑟先生  卢差不多每天输两千
Mr. Reese, Lou's lost nearly $2,000 a day
连续六个月了
for the last six months.
总数超过32万了
Over $320,000 and counting.
一个只有死收入的人怎么能欠这么多债
How does someone on a fixed income accrue that kind of debt?
真正的问题是  卢到底是
The real question is, how the hell did Lou
怎么弄到这些钱的
get all that money in the first place?
卢肯定是借钱赌博想还债
Lou must be borrowing money to gamble himself out of debt.
他的运气坏得史无前例
And since he has the worst luck I've ever seen,
这样情况只会更糟
he's only going to make his situation worse.
但钱是从哪里来的呢
But where is the money coming from?
你得去查查他的老赌友
You should check into his old gambling pals,
看是不是有人出资
see if anyone is staking him.
你想过没
Has it occurred to you,
也许卢自己就是黑帮份子
what if Lou was a mobster himself?
什么  躲起来的老黑手党吗
What, an old Mafioso in hiding?
我当然希望并非如此
I certainly hope that's not the case.
我去盯他
I'll keep an eye on him.
芬奇
Finch...
如果他很危险
if he's dangerous--
我拒绝相信一个老人
I refuse to believe that that old man
能伤害到别人
is capable of hurting anybody.
他脾气是不好  但他不是杀人犯
He's cantankerous, but he's not a killer.
给舍曼斯基打开二号审讯室
Open up interrogation two for Szymanski.
走
Let's go.
-舍曼斯基  -卡特
- Szymanski-- - Carter...
-有人要陷害我  栽赃了证据  -什么
- Somebody's trying to set me up. They planted evidence. - What?
海外账户  迈阿密公寓
Offshore accounts. A condo in Miami.
然后内务部在我房间的枕头里找到那东西
Then IAB finds this stuffed in a pillow in my apartment.
这是内务部的事
This is an Internal Affairs matter.
这是个好警察  到底怎么回事
And this is a good cop. What is going on here?
我们收到可靠线报  结果是真的
We received a reliable tip that turned out to be right.
线报  谁的
A tip? From who?
缉毒组有人从线人处听说的
Somebody in narcotics got word from a CI.
走吧  舍曼斯基
Let's go, Szymanski.
我今天本来要出庭作证  卡特
I'm supposed to testify today, Carter.
他们抹黑我让我无法上庭
They're dirtying me up to keep me off the stand.
法官  彼得・约格洛夫领导俄罗斯黑帮
Judge, Peter Yogorov runs the Russian Mafia.
他正因谋杀受审
He's on trial for murder.
明显是他栽赃了证据
Now obviously he had that evidence planted.
这是赤裸裸的干扰证人
It's clear-cut witness tampering.
我要申请延期到舍曼斯基警探可以作证
Now I plead a continuance until Detective Szymanski can testify.
-我一小时后把他带回  -好的
- I'll have him back in an hour. - All right.
约格洛夫先生  听说地检官失去了起诉你的关键证人
Mr. Yogorov, I heard the ADA lost her key witness in your trial.
你真幸运啊
Lucky you.
-你他妈是谁啊  -去兜兜风吧
- Who the hell are you? - Let's take a ride.
约格洛夫先生
Mr. Yogorov...
我想我们可以相互帮助
I believe we can help each other.
你们是HR  是吧
You're HR, yes?
我听说你们完蛋了
I heard you guys were finished.
你听错了
Well, you heard wrong.
我还听说没人能见到老大
I also heard no one's ever seen the boss.
舍曼斯基警探是你案子的关键
Detective Szymanski is key to your case.
他逮捕了你  检查了犯罪现场
He did the arrest, processed the crime scene.
不过现在他的证词要受到严格检查了
But now his testimony is under scrutiny,
他碰过的东西都要受到质疑了
and everything he's touched is in question.
彼得  我们可以让你和你弟弟
Peter, we can make sure that you and your brother
再也不用接受审判  坐进大牢
never see the inside of a courtroom or jail cell again.
代价呢
In exchange for what?
幕后操纵需要钱
Pulling strings costs money.
我们需要现金  就这么简单
We need cash, plain and simple.
你救我们回家  就成交
You get us back home, we have a deal.
我得说  我没感觉跟踪卢有什么困难
I must say, I'm not finding Lou difficult to tail at all.
也许我应该考虑从事特工职业
Perhaps I should have considered a career in the clandestine arts.
你那面运气如何
Any luck on your mission?
我刚和泽西这边
I just had a little chat with some
有头有脸的混混们聊了下
of the more notable lowlifes here in Jersey,
他们说卢黑帮里的老朋友都已经死了
and they say that all Lou's old mob buddies are dead.
被谋杀吗
Murdered?
自然死亡  卢是唯一还活着的
Natural causes. Lou's the last man standing.
卢的财政状况呢
What about Lou's finances?
他欠了犯罪组织或是高利贷的钱吗
Is he in debt to any criminal outfits or loan sharks?
至少这些人没听说
Not as far as these guys have heard.
看来我们又回到原点了
Guess that puts us right back where we started, huh?
里瑟先生  我认为卢的事
Mr. Reese, I think there may be more to Lou
另有隐情
than meets the eye.
事实上  我觉得我们在赌场见到的很多赌徒
In fact, I think there may be more to many of the gamblers
都另有隐情
we saw at the casino.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
他们中好几个今天也出现在了药店
Several of them are also here at the pharmacy.
而且很奇怪
And it does seem strange
卢连续两天都来取药
that Lou would pick up prescriptions two days in a row.
我觉得需要找个专家帮我们挖掘一下
I think I'll task an expert to help us do a little digging.
我也去挖掘一下
I'll do some digging too.
不是吧
Come on, man.
那家药店归狮木公司所有
The pharmacy is owned by Lionwood Enterprises.
是家我从没听过的皮包公司
It's a shell company if I've ever heard of one.
皮包公司  谁的
A shell? For whom?
有几位董事会成员
There are several board members,
但可巧都联系不到
but they're all conveniently unreachable.
我查了公司的税单
I looked into the tax paperwork,
有一位合伙人不在公开名单上
and there's one partner left off the public listing.
你知道达里恩・马克里斯这名字吗
Does the name Darien Makris mean anything to you?
知道  谢谢  陶先生
It does, indeed. Thank you, Mr. Tao.
你真是帮了大忙
You've been wonderfully helpful.
你跟着我到处转
You're gonna tail me around town,
至少该有胆介绍下自己吧
at least have the stones to introduce yourself, huh?
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on.
我帮你拿
I got it.
坐吧
Sit.
你叫什么
What's your name?
哈罗德・奎尔
Harold Quail.
那哈罗德  你能告诉我
So, Harold, you wanna tell me
为什么今早我离开家后你就一直跟着我吗
why you've been following me since I left my house this morning?
我是国税局的  米切尔先生
I'm with the IRS, Mr. Mitchell.
我正在调查维纳斯赌场
I'm looking into the Venus Casino.
希望可以问你几个问题
I was hoping to ask you a few questions.
-我有什么麻烦吗  -跟我没有
- Am I in trouble? - Not with me.
但我有理由相信你需要帮助
But I have reason to believe that you might need some help.
你从哪弄来那么多钱的
Where did you get all the money?
想从我这得到答案  你得自己赢
You want answers out of me, you have to earn them.
百家乐
Baccarat.
每局一个答案
One answer per hand.
就我看来  米切尔先生
From what I've seen, Mr. Mitchell,
你的运气不怎么好
you're not that lucky.
那对你可是好事  赌吧
Well, this should go well for you. Bet.
玩家
Player.
玩家7点  庄家9点
7 on player, 9 on banker.
太遗憾了
Too bad.
看来你欠我一个答案
Looks like you owe me an answer.
你为什么觉得我需要帮助
Why do you think I need help?
你过去六个月输了32万美元
You've lost $320,000 in the last six months.
我觉得你债台高筑了
I imagine you are in very serious debt.
不  不  行规
No, no, no. House rules.
我发牌
I'm dealing.
庄家
Banker.
真倒霉
Oh, tough luck.
你怎么知道我没那么多钱
How do you know I'm not independently wealthy?
因为我看了你的税务和信用报告
Because I've seen your taxes and your credit reports.
玩家
Player.
你今天不顺啊  哈罗德
This is not your day, Harold.
又输了
You lose again.
怎么
What?
你以为我出千吗  哈罗德
Are you calling me a cheater, Harold?
没人喜欢输不起的人
No one likes a sore loser.
米切尔先生  我确信你处于极度危险中
Mr. Mitchell, I believe that you may be in grave danger.
让我帮助你
Let me help you.
当人们需要帮助时  都会想  "找国税局"
When people need help, they think, "Call the IRS."
这家伙付账
This guy's got the check!
米切尔先生  请听我说
Mr. Mitchell, please, I...
给你  亲爱的
Here you go, hon.
谢谢
Thank you.
喜欢海鲜吗
Hey, you like seafood?
钓吧
Go fish.
天啊
Oh, dear.
看到卢了  芬奇
Got eyes on Lou, Finch.
不过你在哪儿
But where are you?
我决定回图书馆了
I decided to return to the library.
决定
Decided?
卢甩掉你了  是吧
Lou gave you the slip, didn't he?
他把我的钥匙扔进了满是甲壳类的鱼缸里
When he deposited my keys in a tank full of crustaceans,
我深感
I got the distinct impression
他不喜欢被跟踪
that he didn't appreciate being followed.
而且  里瑟先生
And, Mr. Reese,
卢在赌场外运气要好多了
Lou is much luckier outside the walls of the casino.
我认为他在维纳斯赌场是故意输
I think he's throwing those games at the Venus,
但我想不出他为什么要故意输掉自己的钱
but I can't imagine why he would intentionally lose his own money.
你不喜欢老虎机吗
Didn't you like the slots?
不  你知道那东西就是在不断重复
No, you know, it's the same old thing over and over again.
我还是在桌上试试手气吧
I thought I'd try the tables.
里瑟先生  那个头发蓬松的女士
Mr. Reese, that lady with the bouffant,
她输的速度和卢一样
she's losing money at the same rate Lou is.
-然后呢  -她输的时间更长
- So? - She's been doing it longer.
已经输了40万零5千了
She's down $405,000.
那个喜欢用美黑油的女士
And the woman with the fondness for tanning oil,
输了26万1千
$261,000.
这些人都跟卢一起出现过
All of these people that we see with Lou,
他们都输了相当多的钱
they've lost enormous sums of money.
这绝不是巧合
That's more than a coincidence.
他们这么做肯定另有原因
There must be a reason why they're doing that.
你认为他们也是故意输的
You think they're losing intentionally as well?
为什么
Why?
也许我们该问问那个同时拥有赌场和药店的人
Perhaps we should ask the man who owns both the casino and the pharmacy.
维纳斯崛起:  达里恩・马克里斯  大西洋城的新星
马克里斯
Makris.
如果警方是对的  马克里斯在贩毒
If the police are right and Makris is running a drug operation,
那他就需要洗钱
he needs to launder dirty money.
他用老年市民来运钱
He's using senior citizens as couriers.
他们每天在牌桌上把钱输掉
They lose the money at the tables,
通过赌场的现金池洗钱
and it gets laundered into the casino's cash pool every day.
警方绝对不会怀疑到
The police wouldn't think twice about
在赌场里输钱的老年人
old people losing money at a casino.
你知道还有什么警方永远不会怀疑到吗
You know what else the police would never suspect?
去抓处方药的老年人
An old person picking up a prescription.
芬奇
Finch...
那个药房是个秘密传递点
the pharmacy is a dead drop.
马克里斯有一批稳定的运钱者
Makris has got a whole stable of money mules
给他运送现金
transporting cash for him.
他们可不是毒贩
These aren't exactly drug lords.
可以肯定  是马克里斯逼他们的
Safe bet, Makris is forcing them to do this.
但只出现了卢的号码
But Lou's is the only number that came up.
为什么他的处境比其他人要危险
Why is he in more danger than the others?
可能因为他在偷藏这笔非法资金
Maybe because he's skimming off the laundered money.
如果马克里斯发现了
And if Makris has found out,
我想他为了保住自己的钱不惜杀人
I bet he'd kill anyone to protect his investment.
舍曼斯基警探
Detective Szymanski,
你前晚见过安东尼・马可尼吗
did you talk to Anthony Marconi two nights ago?
-没有  绝对没有  -没见过
- No. Absolutely not. - No?
那你们上次会面是什么时候
Then when was the last time you guys talked?
上次我见到这家伙的时候
The last time I talked to that guy,
他的手下开枪打了我
his men shot me.
这是白费劲
It's bad business.
卡尔  那个舍曼斯基的线报来自缉毒组
Cal, the tip came in from narcotics about Szymanski.
你知道是谁打的电话吗
Do you know who made the call?
乔丝
Look, Joss--
是你吗
It was you?
你的线人是谁
Who's your CI?
你知道我不能告诉你
You know I can't tell you that.
去你的不能说
Like hell you can't.
你以为我愿意扳倒另一位警察吗
You think I enjoy taking another cop down?
证据会说话
The evidence speaks for itself.
那我们就什么好说的了
Then I guess there's nothing else to say.
-卡特  -什么事
- Hey, Carter. - Yeah.
我打电话给斯蒂尔斯在51局的上司
I called one of the guys Stills reported to at the 51st--
我们等会再谈行吗  铁尼
Can we talk later, Terney?
行行
Sure, sure.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
有件事你得跟我说实话
I need you to tell me the truth about something.
没有圣诞老人  是你父母扮的
There's no Santa. It was your parents.
严肃点  弗斯科
I'm serious, Fusco.
关于比彻的事
It's about Beecher.
你听说过他的事吗
Have you ever heard anything about him?
卡特  你我联手抓住了很多黑警
Carter, you and I put a bunch of dirty cops away.
但相信我  HR没完蛋
But trust me on this, HR's not gone.
活蹦乱跳着呢
Not by a long shot.
谁都可能是其中一员
Anybody could be on the take.
要说比彻的话  我不清楚
As far as Beecher, I don't know.
但如果你从舍曼斯基的赃款着手
But if you follow that money they found on Szymanski,
也许会有意外收获
you might not like what you find.
你今天筹码输得可真快啊  卢
You burned through those chips fast today, Lou.
你简直是要我命啊  詹  要我命了
You're killing me, Jen, killing me.
明天好运点
Better luck tomorrow.
老东西  你要的爆米花给你拿来了
Hey, old man. Got that popcorn you wanted.
-别挡路  -对不起了  老爷子
- Out of my way. - Sorry, gramps.
你一直在偷藏老板的筹码
You've been skimming from the boss.
我们得赶紧离开这
We gotta get you away from here.
你可以相信我  我是跟
You can trust me. I'm with--
哈罗德一起的
Harold?
是  我猜到了
Yeah, I figured.
我猜你们不是国税局的吧
So I guess you're not really with the IRS, huh?
有这么明显吗
Is it that obvious?
我想你欠哈罗德几个答案
Now I think you owe Harold some answers.
是啊
Yeah.
能告诉我你到底是谁吗
You want to tell me who you really are?
这并不重要
That's not important.
但我说想帮你时
But when I said we want to help you,
是真心话
that was the truth.
你为什么给马克里斯做事
Why are you working for Makris?
我的玛里琳得了癌症
My Marilyn got cancer.
已经是晚期
Really advanced.
我们唯一的希望是一种干细胞疗法
Only hope we had was a stem cell treatment.
我们的积蓄远远不够
We didn't have enough to cover it.
我不得不想法凑钱
I had to improvise.
所以你去了赌场
So you went to the casino.
我之前说对了  是吧
I was right, wasn't I?
那是在侮辱我的技术
That's like calling a white truffle athlete's foot.
我可是大西洋城最牛逼的老千
I'm the best damn card mechanic in Atlantic City.
所以你弄到了钱
So you got the money.
对  也进行了治疗
Yeah, and the treatment.
但有时运气会用光
But sometimes, your luck just runs out.
玛里琳去世没多久
A few days after Marilyn passed,
马克里斯拿到了一份老千的旧名单
Makris got his hands on an old list of card sharps.
你的名字在那名单上  他找上门
He saw your name on the list, and he came around,
让你还钱
asking for his money back,
但你肯定早花光了
but of course you didn't have it.
所以他拿走了你的婚戒
So he takes your wedding ring
和玛里琳的首饰作为抵押
and Marilyn's jewelry as collateral,
然后逼你帮他洗钱
and he puts you to work laundering money.
说是只要干几个月
Said it would just be a couple of months.
但我感觉一辈子都别想脱身
I get a feeling this is a lifetime gig.
所以你开始偷藏吗
So is that why you started skimming?
他让我输的我都输了
I lose everything he tells me to,
为什么我就不能赢回一点点
so what if I win a little back?
明显马克里斯可不这么想
Clearly Makris sees it differently.
卢  我不会让他再追杀你
Lou, I'm not going to let him come after you ever again.
是么
Yeah?
与此同时
In the meantime,
你最好出城避避风头
it would be best if you left town.
这是车票和钱  足够让你过得舒适
Here's a ticket, enough money to keep you comfortable.
在芝加哥给你准备了很棒的住处
There's a lovely place waiting for you in Chicago.
我不能离开玛里琳
I can't leave Marilyn.
我的墓地就在她旁边
There's a plot for me right next to her.
刻好了名字  什么都准备好了
It's got my name on it and everything.
卢  我理解
Lou, I know exactly
被迫抛下一个人的痛苦
how difficult it is to have to leave someone behind.
你也失去过
You lost someone too?
我必须继续生活
I had to move on.
你也是
So must you.
四十年前  黑手党抓住我出千
40 years ago, the mob caught me sharping.
揍了我个半死  打断了我的全部手指
Beat me all to hell, broke all my fingers.
扔下我等死
Left me for dead.
一名女服务员在餐馆后面的垃圾堆里发现了我
A waitress found me in a dumpster behind the diner.
玛里琳
Marilyn.
我已经绝望了
I was ready to give up.
是她给了我活下去的动力  你明白吗
But she gave me something to live for, you know?
为了她  我放弃了赌博
Because of her, I gave up gambling.
而这双手则用来修理手表
I used these hands to fix watches instead.
她拯救了我  哈罗德
She saved me, Harold.
而现在她希望你拯救你自己
And she'd want you to save yourself now.
芝加哥一定很冷
Chicago will be cold.
不用担心  卢
Don't worry, Lou,
我的同伴会让马克里斯相信
my associate will make sure Makris thinks
你已经死了
you've been eliminated.
你觉得我还有可能回来吗
So you think I'll be able to come back?
也许吧  总有机会
Maybe. Eventually.
我这把年纪  没太多机会了
At my age, there's not much eventually left.
卢现在安全了
Lou's safe for now,
但马克里斯会穷追不舍
but Makris will never stop looking for him.
他知道太多内幕
He knows too much.
而且我们也不能把其他
And we can't abandon all the other
被马克里斯控制的老人弃之不顾
elderly people under Makris's thumb.
我们有没有能把他定罪的证据
Do we have the evidence to put him behind bars?
不幸的是  没有
Unfortunately, no.
洗钱的人都有两套账
Money launderers keep two sets of books.
交给国税局看的假账
The cooked numbers you show the IRS,
还有记录违法所得的真账
and the real books to keep track of your extralegal gains.
现在
At the moment,
我拿不到那些账本
those books are beyond my reach.
怎么才能让你拿到呢
Well, what would we need to get them within your reach?
分散注意力
A distraction.
这边请  先生
Here you are, Sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
那里还有个钢管舞杆
There was a stripper pole in that thing.
我认为太堕落了
I feel weirdly grimy.
这家伙贩毒吗
So this guy's dealing drugs?
这么说还算好听的
That's putting it mildly.
根据我看到的财务信息
Based on the financial information I've seen,
他的洗钱所得大概在八位数
he's laundering profits on the order of eight figures.
羡慕啊
I'm jealous.
是义愤  义愤填膺
Angry. I'm angry.
必须阻止他
He must be stopped.
没错  所以  你现在是杰森・鲍
Indeed. Ergo, you are now Jason Bao,
花花公子  百万富翁
playboy millionaire.
欢迎来到维纳斯赌场  鲍先生
Welcome to the Venus, Mr. Bao.
-谢谢  先生  -这边请
- Thank you, Sir. - Right this way.
大赌家开始下大注的时候
When a high roller starts betting big,
马克里斯和他的保安就会开始关注
Makris and his security pay attention.
他们都在看你  就没人注意我们了
If they're all looking at you, they won't be watching us.
到了  就是这里
That's it, right up here.
这儿多少钱
How much is this?
一百万美元  如您所愿
$1 million, as you requested.
能上一些龙舌兰酒吗
Can we get some tequila shots, please?
马上就来
Right away.
一百万
A million?
你放心把这么多钱交给里昂吗
You trust Leon with that much of your money?
绝对不放心  不过做生意总得先投资
Absolutely not, but I'm afraid it's the cost of doing business.
祝你好运
Good luck.
运气  那可不够  里瑟先生
Luck? Merely a construct, Mr. Reese.
找到赌场服务器了  很快就好
Found the casino's servers. This shouldn't take long.
至少让里昂开心一下
Let Leon have a little fun at least.
芬奇  你不是送卢出城了吗
Finch, I thought you sent Lou out of town.
是的
I did.
送得不够远  他又回来了
Well, not far enough. He's back.
好像他把偷藏的筹码全赌上了
And it looks like he's gambling every chip he's ever skimmed.
玩家赢
Player bet wins.
他知不知道自己在干什么
Does he have any idea what he's doing?
马克里斯以为他死了
Makris thinks he's dead.
马克里斯肯定不会高兴看见一个死人
Makris is not gonna like it when he sees a dead guy
在赢他的钱
winning his money.
有人想跟你说句话  现在
Someone would like a word, now.
我会还给你车票钱的
Look, I'll pay you back for the ticket.
卢  我们正在获取马克里斯的私人文件
Lou, we're accessing Makris's personal files
想要找到能给他定罪的证据
in search of the proof we need to put him away.
我们不能分出精力来同时保护你
We can't do that and protect you at the same time.
我发过誓  哈罗德
I made a promise, Harold,
向玛里琳发的誓  就在她死前
to Marilyn, right before she passed.
她抓住我的胳膊  她知道我在想什么
She grabbed my arm. She knew what I was thinking.
我在想  或许我应该跟她一起去
That--that maybe I'd, you know, join her.
她对我说  她救我一命
And she told me she didn't save my life,
不是为了让我虚度生命
so I could throw it away.
你没有
And you haven't.
洗毒品黑钱  那种生活吗
Laundering drug money? That's living?
现在一逃了之
And now to just run away?
不不  我要从他口袋里拿回我放进去的每一分钱
No. No, I'm taking back every dime I put in his pocket.
求你了
Please.
我不想到死都是输家
I don't want to die a loser.
很好
Very well.
如果我们要做  就得做好
Then if we're gonna do this, we're gonna do it right.
我觉得你可以从马克里斯手里赢走不止32万
I think you can take Makris for more than the 320,000.
但要想赢大钱  就得下大注
But to win big, you have to bet big.
我出资
So I'm staking you.
你最好像你说的那么厉害
And you'd better be as good as you say you are.
两百万美元  米切尔先生  祝您好运
$2 million, Mr. Mitchell. Good luck.
天牌九点  玩家赢
Natural nine. Player bet wins.
里瑟先生  他赢得越多  就越受关注
The more he wins, Mr. Reese, the more attention he'll get.
你得跟紧他
You'll have to keep close watch on him.
芬奇  抓紧拿资料了
Finch, hurry up and get those documents.
失陪一下
Pardon me.
埃里克・波义尔  保安主管
你派去杀卢的打手
The goons you sent to kill Lou,
在一辆开往佛蒙特州的出租车的后备箱里
they're in the trunk of a taxi headed to Vermont.
你以为这就能阻止我了吗
You think that's gonna stop me?
里瑟先生  我找到真账本了
Mr. Reese, I've found the real books.
现在发给你
I'm e-mailing them to you now.
让你的保安乖一点
Your security will play nice,
不然国税局和联调局就会看见这个东西
or the IRS and the FBI will see this.
账目明细
你就让他玩吧
You're gonna let him play.
分析
累计赢局比例: 78%
概率异常
确认为反常模式
分析
累计赢局比例: 88%
确认为反常模式
我完事了
I'm finished.
里昂在哪儿
Where's Leon?
你让我想起了一个女孩
You remind me of a girl...
凯蒂
Candi.
你有没有想过染成粉色头发
Have you ever considered pink hair?
2032万
$20,320,000.
直接存入我的账户
Direct deposit.
卢易斯・米切尔
Louis Mitchell.
马克里斯先生
Mr. Makris.
恭喜您  米切尔先生
Congratulations, Mr. Mitchell.
转入户名:卢易斯・米切尔
转账完成
不敢相信  我以为我死定了呢
I can't believe it. I thought I was gonna die.
芬奇  我们出来了  芬奇
Finch, we're out. Finch?
他叫这个名字吗
Is that his name?
我们找到了你的朋友  芬奇
We found your friend Finch.
还有鲍先生
And Mr. Bao.
分不清真假可开不了赌场
You can't run a casino without being able to spot a fake.
我本想悄悄搞定
I was gonna do this quietly,
但现在我们要找点乐子了
but now we're gonna have some fun.
卢  那天可真是惊喜啊
Lou, I had such a nice surprise the other day.
一个发牌员告诉我你的好运终于来了
A dealer told me that your luck had finally turned.
你揣走了500美元
You walked away $500 up.
那时我才发现  你一直在偷藏
And that's when I realized you've been skimming.
在我眼皮子底下顺走了好几万
Tens of thousands of dollars, right under my nose.
听我说
Listen--
你只要去输钱就行  老东西
All you had to do was lose, old man.
在你死之前
So before you die,
我会让你明白
I'm gonna make you realize
你就是个输家
that you are a loser.
你永远都是
And that's all you're ever gonna be.
你喜欢玩游戏是吗  卢
You like games, right, Lou?
俄罗斯轮盘是我的最爱
Roulette's my favorite.
你的对手只有左轮手枪
It's just you versus the wheel.
你或许能逃过一两发
You may skate by for a spin or two.
但最终  赢的永远是庄家
But in the end, the house always wins.
我把钱全都还给你  别
I'll give you all the money back, just don't--
别这样  住手
Just stop this. Just stop it.
他没事
Oh, he's safe.
暂时的
For now.
拜托  你得救我啊
Come on, man. You gotta save me.
这是你的活儿
That's your thing!
也不是他
Not him either.
胜率越来越小了啊
The odds are getting worse.
有时运气会用光
Sometimes your luck just runs out.
笨蛋
Hey, dumbass...
我出千了
I cheated.
我也不是说还在为凯蒂哭泣
It's not like I'm still crying over Candi.
但每次都这样  你懂不
But it's always the same story, you know?
找到一个喜欢的女孩
You find a girl you like.
又高挑  又漂亮
She's tall, she's pretty,
结果却是有人花钱雇她把你铐在床上
and it turns out someone paid her to handcuff you to a bed,
想杀死你
so they could murder you.
向来如此
Same old story.
我得学学保护自己了
I gotta learn to protect myself.
或许像你们这样  保护别人
Maybe protect other people like you guys.
听起来不错
That sounds like a great plan.
我升华了  兄弟
I'm turning over a new leaf, dude.
什么
What?
救人要花钱的啊
Saving people costs money!
卡特
Carter.
匆匆忙忙干什么
What's the rush?
我认为舍曼斯基是被陷害的
I think Szymanski was set up.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
弗斯科  你说要从赃款着手是对的
Fusco, you were right about following the money.
知道内务部在舍曼斯基家发现的那些做了标记的钞票吗
You know those marked bills IAB found in Szymanski's place?
联调局把钱安排在了以利亚的一家杂货店里
Well, the FBI placed them in a bodega run by Elias.
六天后  纽约警方突击了那里
Six days later, NYPD did a raid there,
但那些标记钞票没被收进证物
but the marked bills never showed up in evidence.
而是失踪了
They just disappeared.
要么是以利亚挪走了那些钱
So either Elias moved the money
要么就是队里有人拿走了
or someone on the force grabbed it,
给了HR一个陷害好警察的绝佳手段
giving HR a perfect way to set up a good cop.
卡特  警察工作做到家了
Carter, that's real police work.
这足够让内务部放开他了
That should be enough to get IAB off his back.
绝对能在今天之内把他保释出来
It was definitely enough to get him out on bail by the end of the day.
还能让他出庭指证约格洛夫一伙
And it should let him testify against the Yogorovs.
卡特
Carter.
卡尔・比彻来电
怎么
Yeah?
这意味着有人要害舍曼斯基
This means someone does have it out for Szymanski.
你也要多加谨慎
You watch your back.
你也不想下一个轮到你
You don't want them turning on you next.
卡尔・比彻来电
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道你赢来的钱都会被作为证据
I understand your winnings are tied up as evidence.
没事  无所谓
Yeah, well, it doesn't matter.
只要能把马克里斯关进监狱
As long as it keeps Makris locked up.
你说谎时的表情还得再练练
You know, your poker face needs work.
那笔钱你另有打算
You had plans for that money.
我知道你为什么要偷藏那些钱
I figured out why you skimmed all that cash,
想用来买什么
what you wanted to buy.
买什么
What's that?
餐馆
A diner.
那就是你和玛里琳  对吧
That's you and Marilyn, isn't it?
是的  四十年来这里就像我们的家
Yeah, this place was a home to us for 40 years,
但店主总是威胁说要关掉
but the owner kept threatening to shut it down.
我想这里继续
I wanted to keep it alive.
现在马克里斯的开价没戏了
But now that Makris's offer is off the table,
问题解决了
problem solved.
直到再有人开价
Until another offer comes along.
是啊  没有什么是永恒的
Yeah, well, nothing lasts forever.
我一直想找个人看看这个
I've been meaning to have someone look at this.
价值两百万美金的表
That's a $2-million watch.
原来是  不幸的是  我踩了一脚
It was. Unfortunately, I stepped on it.
但如果有人愿意修修
But if someone was interested in repairing it...
知道吗  你妻子  你失去的那个人
You know, your wife, the one you lost.
她失去了一个好男人
She lost a good man.
她现在正在天上对你微笑呢
She's smiling down on you right now.
等等
Wait.
难道她没死
You mean she's not dead?
对于一个天才来说  你就是个白痴
You know, for a genius, you're an idiot.
太迟了  卢
It's too late, Lou.
你还没咽气  就不迟
You're still breathing. It's not too late.
去找她  哈罗德
Go to her, Harold.
就今天  趁你还有时间
Today, while you still have time.
你还好吗
You all right?
我听到卢对你说的话了
I heard what Lou said to you.
你有在听吗
You were listening?
永远在
Always.
你这么做是为了她的安全  哈罗德
You did what you had to do to keep her safe, Harold.
卢不明白
Lou doesn't know that.
但我懂
But I do.
如果我回到之前的生活
And if I were to return to my old life,
最终会搭上格蕾斯的生活
it would eventually cost Grace hers.
总有人无法和爱人一起白头
Some of us don't get to grow old with the one we love.
让我说  卢是最幸运的人
You ask me, Lou's the luckiest guy I know.
我会和她一起白头  里瑟先生  只是天各一方
I'll grow old with her, Mr. Reese, just from afar.
其他的  不想为好
And beyond that, it's best not to think about it.
未知来电
谁
Who is this?
告诉你老大  交易取消了
Tell your boss the deal's off.
他们没撤销案子
They didn't drop the case.
地检又增加了几条指控
The ADA just added more charges.
干扰证人
Witness tampering.
我就不应该相信一个老东西
I should have known not to trust an old man.
约格洛夫
You know, Yogorov,
你真应该对我的老大多点信任
you really ought to have more faith in my boss.
正如你们所知  市长非常关注
As you know, the mayor is very invested
约格洛夫一伙的案子
in this case against the Yogorovs.
因此他让我  他的幕僚长
So he's asked me, his chief of staff,
来确认此案能排除阻碍  正常进行
to ensure that the case is moving forward, despite recent setbacks.
针对舍曼斯基警探的指控
These charges against Detective Szymanski
是HR一手策划的
have HR written all over them.
我们在这起俄罗斯黑手党案上
We've been working on this case against the Russian Mafia
跟进了近十年
for nearly a decade.
我们不会放过约格洛夫一伙
We are not gonna let the Yogorovs go anywhere.
他们吓不倒我们  止不住我们
They can't intimidate us, and they can't stop us.
我们会把约格洛夫兄弟关起来
We're gonna put the Yogorov brothers away
直到他们的孙子都忘记他们的名字
until their grandkids can't remember their names.
我就想听到这个
Exactly what I want to hear.
铁尼警探
Detective Terney...
知道怎么说吗
Are we clear on the story?
杀手从后门逃跑了
Shooter ran out the back?
右肩膀
Right shoulder.
明白  老大
You got it, boss.